So, the exercise asked us to put this
这道练习要求我们将这个 angle 变量放在这里
angle's variable with a long list of numbers in it right here.
这个变量是一个很长的数字列表
Then we needed to write a loop that would use the values from that list.
然后我们需要编写一个循环并使用该列表中的值
The loop started for angle in angles,
循环以 for angle in angles 开头
and then we had to write the statements inside the loop.
然后我们需要在循环中编写语句
Inside the loop, we wanted the turtle to turn right, but how far?
在此循环中 我们希望 turn 右转 但是转多少角度呢？
On each step, we wanted to turn by an angle that's been taken from this list.
在每一步 我们都希望按照这个列表中的值转动
There's a variable created by the loop that will do just that.
循环创建了一个可以执行该操作的变量
This is the angle variable.
这是 angle 变量
So, to get the turtle named builder to turn right by that angle,
要使叫做 builder 的 turtle 按照该角度右转
we say builder.right (angle).
我们输入 builder.right(angle)
Remember, each time the loop runs,
每次循环运行时
this variable will get assigned an item from this list.
都会将此列表中的一项赋值给该变量
The first time through the loop the variable get assigned negative 90,
第一次循环时 将 -90 赋值给该变量
the second time through the loop it'll get zero.
第二次循环时 赋值 0
So, it won't turn at all,
因此不右转
then zero again, then negative 90 and so on.
然后再次是 0 然后是 -90 等等
After it turns we want it to go forward 25.
右转后 我们希望向前移动 25 个像素
We know how to do that builder.forward(25).
我们知道如何实现 输入 builder.forward(25)
Let's run this code and see what happens.
运行代码 看看会发生什么
Hey, look.
快看
It looks like a house, or maybe an arrow.
看起来像一座房子 或者是一个箭头
So, this program shows us something interesting about numbers.
这个程序演示了关于数字的有趣现象
They can mean different things depending on how they're used.
它们可以具有不同的含义 取决于使用方式
In the code that you've seen in this course,
对于你在这门课程中见到的代码
we've used a list of numbers to mean several different things.
我们使用了数字列表来表示不同的事物
In the very first examples with George and Amy,
在一开始的 George 和 Amy 示例中
the actual numbers in the list weren't used at all.
列表中的实际数字根本没使用
We just use the list length to control how many sides the turtle drew;
我们只使用了列表长度来控制 turtle 画多少条边
four sides for a square,
画出方形的四条边
or five for a pentagon.
或者五角星的五条边
On the page with Dizzy,
在 Dizzy 示例中
the turtle who drew a blue square spiral,
turtle 画出了一个蓝色的方形螺旋
we used the numbers in the list to control the lengths of the side.
我们使用列表中的数字控制边的长度
Here, building this house,
现在 在画这座房子时
we're using the numbers to control the angles of the turtle's turns.
我们使用数字控制 turtle 转动的角度
The number 90 could be used as a length or as an angle.
数字 90 可以作为长度或角度
If we pass 90 to the forward method,
如果向 forward 方法传递 90
then the turtle treats it as a length.
那么 turtle 会将它视作长度
But if we pass it to the right or left method the turtle treats it as an angle.
但是如果将其传递给 right 或 left 方法 turtle 会将其视作角度
This is something you will see over and over in your future as a programmer.
以后作为程序员 你会经常见到这种现象
A values type doesn't tell you everything about the meaning of that value.
值类型并不能告诉关于该值的所有信息
It's up to you as the programmer to think through whether
作为程序员 由你来思考
a particular numerical value is meant to be a distance,
特定的数字值是否要被视为距离
an angle, account, an amount of money, or something else.
角度 计数 金额或其他事物